iship.com 2016-08-10

# 

**Effective Date: Jul 12, 2016**

Privacy is important to iShip, Inc., and its subsidiaries (‘iShip’). This Privacy Notice applies to personal information of iShip customers and consumers who use our publicly accessible websites and online services. We refer to these individuals and entities below as ‘you.’

This Privacy Notice does not control the use of information by shipping carriers (e.g., UPS and others)(collectively, ‘Carrier(s)’), or the use of information by shipping service centers (e.g., The UPS Store) or their designated affiliates, agents, or franchisors (collectively, ‘Shipping Service Center(s)’). Please review the privacy policies or notices of the applicable Carrier(s) and/or Shipping Service Center(s) to learn how they treat information they may collect or receive.

## **1\. Information We Gather**

We gather information through activities related to iShip’s shipping services and enterprise solutions (‘iShip Shipping’) such as (a) iShip Shipping and account setup, installation and/or configuration, (b) your management of your account(s) with iShip, (c) tracking and delivery of shipments, (d) communications with you about iShip Shipping, (e) events in which you participate, and (f) surveys, promotions and other offers. 

We may gather the following types of information (some jurisdictions restrict the collection of certain information, in which case such information will not be collected or retained in that jurisdiction):

  * Individual information, such as first and last name, home or other physical address, including street and city name, telephone or fax number, email address, other contact information, and payment information
  * Shipping information, including to provide shipping services or fee-estimates for shipping services; shipping information includes, for example, (i) shipping-related contact details such as the shipper's and consignee's name, physical address, zip or postal code, email address and telephone number, (ii) copy of signature for proof of delivery, (iii) Carrier account number and related information, (iv) package weight and dimensions, and (v) other information required by Carriers, or by a particular Carrier selected by you, and information regarding the content of certain shipments
  * Shipping information, including to provide shipping services or fee-estimates for shipping services; shipping information includes, for example, (i) shipping-related contact details such as the shipper's and consignee's name, physical address, zip or postal code, email address and telephone number, (ii) copy of signature for proof of delivery, (iii) Carrier account number and related information, (iv) package weight and dimensions, and (v) other information required by Carriers, or by a particular Carrier selected by you, and information regarding the content of certain shipments
  * Other information you voluntarily provide to us, such as in connection with iShip Shipping or stored in your account, such as address information, shipping history, tracking numbers (for example, when requesting shipment tracking), and information connected with supplemental iShip Shipping services such as custom declaration information for international destinations
  * Information that enables us to verify an individual's identity
  * Names, email addresses and telephone numbers of others to whom we are asked to send information
  * Information provided in response to surveys
  * Username, password and other credentials used to access iShip Shipping or Carrier products and services
  * Social media user names or identifiers, content and other data posted on our official social media pages or elsewhere on the Internet (such as other public locations), or which you allow to be shared through social media platforms
  * Payment information (including payment card details or online payment services number and billing address) and financial information (such as bank account number)
  * Tax identification number (in some cases, this may be a social security number) in circumstances in which you request products or services for which this information is required, or in connection with certain promotions, sweepstakes, or surveys
  * Other information that may be provided to us in connection with an iShip product or service

## **2\. Additional Online Information Gathering**

When you visit our websites or use our online services we may collect certain information through automatic means, such as logging. This may include information such as your IP address, type of browser and operating system used, information regarding your internet service provider or the type of device you used to access our websites, date and time of such access, pages you visit, and other sites you may visit that link to or from our websites. We may also collect information through the use of cookies, clear gifs, device identifiers, or other identifiers or technologies, including as those technologies may evolve over time (collectively, ‘Data Technologies’). We may use Data Technologies to identify and track your visits and use of our websites, to customize your experience on our websites or online services, to “remember” your passwords, and for storing information or settings. We also use Data Technologies to save preferences and session data entered by you while using iShip Shipping services, access information of registered users at login, to improve the iShip Shipping services and for other internal business purposes.

We may allow third parties to include Data Technologies on our websites, or collect personal information about our visitors’ activities over time and across websites, services, or online applications, including those that are not operated by us. Information collected by Data Technologies may be used on our websites or on other websites, services, or online applications, including those that are not operated by us. To learn more about third parties’ information practices, please refer to those third parties’ privacy policies or notices.

We may link certain data elements we have collected through automated means, such as your browser information, with other information we have gathered about you. For example, linking such as this potentially enables us to identify whether you have opened an email we sent to you. iShip may also combine information gathered from cookies or log files with other information in order to provide and improve iShip Shipping services, to enhance our ability to communicate with our customers about additional services they may find of value and for other internal business purposes.

We also may use third-party analytics tools that collect information about visitor traffic on our websites.

You may be able to modify your browser’s or device’s setting to decline certain Data Technologies, such as cookies, if you prefer. However, some features or functions of our websites may not function properly if you do so.

For your convenience and information, we may provide links to websites, apps, places and services that may be operated by companies other than iShip. These companies may have their own privacy policies or notices, which we strongly suggest you review. Our services also may be made available to you through third-party platforms (such as providers of app stores) or through other third-party channels. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any non-iShip websites, places or services.

## **3\. How We Use the Information We Gather**

We may use the information we gather to:

  * Provide products and services you request or to fulfill a service agreement with you, including iShip Shipping
  * Process and collect payments, set prices, and establish credit
  * Provide customer support and communicate with you, including, for example, in response to your requests, questions and comments
  * Establish and manage your account (including your online account on iShip.com and its various features, such as the address book)
  * Offer you products and services we believe may interest you
  * Communicate about, and administer your participation in, special events, programs, surveys, contests, sweepstakes, and other offers or promotions
  * Send information to your contacts (such as package recipients, or those designated to receive status or tracking updates) if you ask us to do so
  * Process claims we receive in connection with our services
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; determining the effectiveness of our sales, marketing and advertising; analyzing and enhancing our products, services and websites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities)
  * Perform data analyses (including market and consumer research, trend analysis, financial analysis, and anonymization of personal information)
  * Protect against, identify and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims and other liabilities, and to protect the interests of you, us, or others
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements, government regulations, and our policies

We may supplement data we collect through automated means with information about your location (such as your ZIP or postal code) to provide you with content that may be of interest to you. We also use this information to help diagnose technical and service problems, administer our websites, identify users of our websites, and gather demographic information about our users. Our websites and online services are not designed to respond to “do not track” requests from browsers.

We also may use the information we gather about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection (where permitted). In addition, iShip may use your information with your consent or as approved by you from time to time.

## **4\. Information We Share**

iShip shares information with Carriers and Shipping Service Centers in connection with providing the services you request. Shipping information may be shared with shippers, consignees, recipients, and third party payors. In some cases, information may be shared with businesses whose customer has received or is shipping a package. This Privacy Notice does not control how such recipients, consignees, third party payors, businesses, Carriers and/or Shipping Service Centers (collectively, ‘Potential Recipients’) use the information they receive. You should consult the privacy policies or notices of each such Potential Recipient to learn more about how they handle the information they receive.

In addition, iShip may employ service providers, partners, or affiliates to perform functions on its behalf, and these services may involve processing personal information. For example, these service providers, partners, and affiliates may be authorized to collect, use, or disclose personal information in order to:

  * Help resolve customer service requests
  * Provide package shipment services, such as printing postage labels
  * Help iShip test and create new product and service features
  * Help iShip manage its information technology
  * Provide legal, privacy, or security support or advice
  * Otherwise support iShip’s operations

We also may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, regulation or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena), (ii) in response to requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal or fraudulent activity. We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you if we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation). In the event that all or a portion of iShip, or substantially all of the assets of iShip, is sold to another business entity, including a Carrier, personal information gathered by iShip will likely be included among the assets transferred to such business entity. iShip will provide you notice of any such event as set forth in Updates to Our Privacy Notice.

This Privacy Notice does not apply to anonymized or aggregated data which by itself does not allow an individual to be located or contacted. iShip may use and share such anonymized or aggregated data with third parties.

## **5\. Your Options**

We offer you certain choices about how we communicate with you and what information we collect from you. You may choose not to receive marketing email communications from us by clicking on the unsubscribe link in our marketing emails. Visit the privacy policies of the applicable Shipping Service Centers and Carriers to learn about their marketing practices.

## **6\. Access and Correction**

Registered users of iShip Shipping with administrative privileges to their iShip account can review, modify, or delete certain information previously provided by editing their account profile. This information may include but is not limited to account information (which allows you to update your contact information and iShip marketing preferences), password, Carrier designation (which allows you to change your selected and/or preferred Carriers), applications (which allows you to choose whether to view certain advanced shipping options) and payment information. It may also include address book information. If you have questions or problems concerning your account, contact your Shipping Service Center or your company's designated support contact, who may contact iShip if necessary.

## **7\. How We Protect Personal Information**

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. We do not maintain security for Shipping Service Centers or Carriers. You should know that information that is located on the outside of a package or letter may be visible to others.

## **8\. Data Transfers**

We may transfer the information we gather to countries other than the country in which the information originally was collected. Your personal information may be stored in the United States. In addition, your personal information may be transferred to and stored in any country where you choose to ship a package. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Notice and in accordance with applicable law.

## **9\. California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 entitles California users to request information concerning the disclosure of certain personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. California users who wish to request further information in compliance with this law may contact us as specified in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

## **10\. Updates to Our Privacy Notice**

This Privacy Notice may be updated periodically and, where permitted by law, without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices. Any such revisions will be noted here. We will indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated.

## **11\. How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by email at [privacy@iShip.com](mailto:privacy@iShip.com). You also may write to us at:

General Manager  
iShip, Inc.   
3545 Factoria Blvd SE #100  
Bellevue WA 98006  

**_Addendum to Privacy Notice for Canada_**

iShip may establish and maintain a file of your personal information for the purposes described above, which will be accessible at 3545 Factoria Blvd SE #100, Bellevue, WA 98006, USA. Authorized employees, agents and mandataries of iShip who require access to your personal information to fulfil their job requirements will have access to your personal information. If you wish to request access or correction of your personal information in our custody or control, you may write to:

Attention: General Manager  
iShip, Inc.   
3545 Factoria Blvd SE #100  
Bellevue WA 98006

Your right to access or correct your personal information is subject to applicable legal restrictions. We may take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. If you wish to make inquiries or complaints or have other concerns about our personal information practices, you may write to us at General Manager as described above, e-mail us at [privacy@iship.com](mailto:privacy@iShip.com) or telephone us at 877.994.7447. 

Personal information maintained and processed by our service providers in the United States and other foreign jurisdictions may be subject to disclosure pursuant to a lawful access request by United States or foreign courts or government authorities.
